Guide to the Intelsat Agreement Negotiating History Records, 1961-1998 MS2186
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Draft agreements, 1969 January - 1971 February; Series 4
  - Intergovernmental Agreement drafts February 16 1971, 1971 February 16; Series 4 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Intergovernmental Agreement drafts February 19 1971, 1971 February 19; Series 4 (Box 23, Folder 4)
- Final documents, 1967 October - 1971 August 20 and undated; Series 5
  Arranged in original order of definitive arrangements.
  This series includes final agreements, often referred to as "definitive arrangements" for INTELSAT, as well as associated annex documents, operating agreements, and related meeting notes.
  - 1964 Agreement Establishing Interim Arrangements for a Global Commercial Communications Satellite System and Special Agreement, 1968 December 18; Series 5 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Final Texts of Definitive Arrangements, 1971 May 25; Series 5 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Final Texts of Definitive Arrangements, Annexes A-D, 1971 May 21; Series 5 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Signatures to Final Agreement, 1971 May 21; Series 5 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Intelsat Operating Agreement and Annex, 1971 May 19; Series 5 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Negotiating History of Final Text, 1971 June 17 - 1971 july 7; Series 5 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Summary of Definitive Arrangements and Comparison with Interim Arrangements, 1971 July 2; Series 5 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Annex of Cost Comparison Ownership Plans, 1969 March 7; Series 5 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Index to Definitive Arrangements, ICSC documents 28 through 35, 1968 October 3 - 1971 July 7; Series 5 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Definitive Arrangements, ICSC documents 28-40 to 30-36, 1968 October 3 - 1971 July 7; Series 5 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Definitive Arrangements, ICSC documents 31-23 to 33-63, 1968 October 3 - 1971 July 7; Series 5 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Definitive Arrangements, ICSC documents 34-12 to 34-139, 1968 October 3 - 1971 July 7; Series 5 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Definitive Arrangements, ICSC documents 35-4 to 35-117, 1968 October 3 - 1971 July 7; Series 5 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Definitive Arrangements, ICSC document 35-118: Report of Interim Communications Satellite Committee, 1968 October 3 - 1971 July 7; Series 5 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Final INTELSAT Agreement, August 20 1971 (folder 1 of 3),contains index, 1971 August 20; Series 5 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Final INTELSAT Agreement, August 20 1971 (folder 2 of 3), 1971 August 20; Series 5 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Final INTELSAT Agreement, August 20 1971 (folder 3 of 3), 1971 August 20; Series 5 (Box 25, Folder 3)
- Vertical files, Directors' General, 1973 August 8 - 1998 June 17; Series 6
  Arranged chronologically by director administration.
  This series includes documents relating to election procedures for the Director General of INTELSAT (also called Secretary General, also called Inspector General), including election regulations, voting records, and notes. Materials date from 1970-1998, and cover the directorships of Santiago Astrain, Richard Colino, dean Burch, Irving Goldstein, and Conny Kullman. Also included are materials related to campaigns for director, including biographies, correspondence. For some directors, materials from their adminstration is also included, such as speeches or notes of thanks. Also included are materials relating to the dismissal of Richard Colino and related lawsuit.
  - Selection of Director General (Santiago Astrain), records 1970-73, 1970 - 1973 August 3; Series 6 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Election of Director General (Santiago Astrain), records 1975-77, 1975 March 18- 1977 February 28; Series 6 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Election of Director General (Richard Colino), records 1983 (folder 1 of 4), 1982 September 1 - 1984 February 13; Series 6 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Election of Director General (Richard Colino), records 1983, 1982 September 1 - 1984 February 13; Series 6 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Election of Director General (Richard Colino), records 1983 (folder 3 of 4), 1982 September 1 - 1984 February 13; Series 6 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Election of Director General (Richard Colino), records 1983 (folder 4 of 4), 1982 September 1 - 1984 February 13; Series 6 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Election of Director General (Dean Burch), records 1987 (folder 1 of 3), 1986 December 11- 1987 March 12; Series 6 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Election of Inspector General (Dean Burch), records 1987 (folder 2 of 3), 1986 December 11- 1987 March 12; Series 6 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Election of Director General (Dean Burch), records 1987 (folder 3 of 3), 1986 December 11- 1987 March 12; Series 6 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Election of Director General (Irving Goldstein), records 1991, 1991 September - 1991 December 31; Series 6 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Foreign Travel records related to Goldstein candidacy, 1991, 1991 September 28 - 1991 November 25; Series 6 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Goldstein candidacy strategy records, 1991, 1991 September 20 and undated; Series 6 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Goldstein candidacy Press Clippings, 1991, 1991 September - 1991 December; Series 6 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Goldstein candidacy internal documentation, 1991, 1991 November - 1991 December; Series 6 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Director General Election Documentation, 1991, 1991 September 17 - 1992 February 12; Series 6 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - State Department Correspondence regarding Goldstein candidacy, 1991, 1991 September 21- 1991 November 25; Series 6 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - United Kingdom correspondence regarding Goldstein candidacy, 1991, 1991 August 1 - 1991 November 8; Series 6 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - remarks by Irving Goldstein, 1991, 1991 October 14 - 1991 December 13; Series 6 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Irving Goldstein congratulatory correspondence, 1991-92, 1991 December 8 - 1992 January 9; Series 6 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Irving Goldstein correspondence of thanks, 1991-92, 1991 October 4 - 1992 January 10; Series 6 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Election of Director General (Conny Kullman), records 1998 (folder 1 of 3), 1998 March 3 - 1998 June 17; Series 6 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Election of Director General (Conny Kullman), records 1998 (folder 2 of 3), 1998 March 3 - 1998 June 17; Series 6 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Election of Director General (Conny Kullman), records 1998, 1998 March 3 - 1998 June 17; Series 6 (Box 28, Folder 8)
- Technical reports, 1971 October 6 - 1978 July 3; 1976-1977; series 7
  Arranged by committee or meeting where a technical report was created.
  This series contains technical documents, sometimes referred to as "annexes" in paper descriptions and indexes of the collection; these materials, dating 1968-1971, relate to the technical reports and findings produced by the various panels created during the negotiation process. Included are documents relating to technical issues, financial issues, and marketing plans. These are organized by the committee or working group that prepared them.
  There were four major meetings of the Preparatory Committee, I, II, III, and IV, and most of the documents were products of one of these meetings. Other documents come from intersessional meetings or independent working group panels. Some groups provided indexes of documents, others did not. In some cases, document numbers or portions of documents may be missing or incomplete.
  - INMARSAT Prepcom I, Index to documents 1-23, 1976 July 23; Series 7 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - INMARSAT Prepcom I, documents 1-10, 1976 December 2- 1977 January 21; series 7 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - INMARSAT Prepcom I, documents 24-66, 1976 October 26 - 1977 January 14; series 7 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - INMARSAT Prepcom I, documents 67-83, 1976 October 26 - 1977 January 14; series 7 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Economic, Marketing, and Financial Panel documents, 1977 August; series 7 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Working Group on Maritime Satellites, documents (folder 1 of 2), 1975 June 30 - 1975 October 6; series 7 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Working Group on Maritime Satellites, documents (folder 2 of 2), 1975 November 7- 1975 December 5; series 7 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - INMARSAT PrepCom Working Group 2, reports, 1977 June 16 - 1977 October 20; series 7 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - PrepCom Technical Panel, reports, 1977 April 1 - 1978 February 3; series 7 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - PrepCom, Report of the Third Session of the Technical Panel, 1978 February 21; series 7 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - INTELSAT options for Maritime Space Segment Capacity, 1978 February 8; series 7 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Technical Panel, Report of Transmission Requirements, 1977 August 3; series 7 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - INMARSAT PrepCom V, reports, 1979 February 9 - 1979 May 17; series 7 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Economic, Marketing, and Financial Panel, report of First Session, 1977 may 12; series 7 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Economic, Marketing, and Financial Panel, reports of Second Session, 1977 August 22; series 7 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - INMARSAT PrepCom III, documents 67-70, 1977 September 1 - 1977 December 9; series 7 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - INMARSAT PrepCom III, documents 71-94, 1977 September 1 - 1977 December 9; series 7 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - INMARSAT PrepCom III, various reports, 1977 May 13 - 1978 July 20; series 7 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - INMARSAT PrepCom IV, various reports, 1977 November 27 - 1978 December 21; series 7 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Maritime Satellites International Organizational Plan, 1971 October 6; series 7 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Organizational Panel Documents (First Working Group), 1977 June 13 - 1978 July 3 and undated; series 7 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - INMARSAT PrepCom II, various reports, 1977 October 13 - 1977 October 20; series 7 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - INMARSAT PrepCom II, documents 1- 17 and index, 1977 January 10 - 1977 February 8 and undated; series 7 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - INMARSAT PrepCom II, documents 19-39, 1977 February 15 - 1977 April 12 and undated; series 7 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    document 18, "Ship Terminal Reliability Study", as listed in index, not found.
  - INMARSAT PrepCom II, documents 40-65, 1977 April 28 - 1977 June 17 and undated; series 7 (Box 32, Folder 6)